Do you have all of your belongings with you?
Do you have your lunch,
water bottle, and snacks?
Yes!
Fujimoto, Kobato, you have everything, do you?
Yes.
We're going on a picnic.
You're not taking anything?
I'm sorry! I'll go and get my bag!
Kobato, are you all right?
Y-Yes I'm fine.
Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
...Hide-and-Seek.
Oh, it's you, Kobato.
Ioryogi-san, let's go!
We're all going on a picnic now!
Oh I see. I thought you seemed awfully excited.
Yes. Everyone is very excited!
So come with us, Ioryogi-san!
Could be fun.
Oh, u-um...
What are you waiting for?! Pick up the phone!
Y-Yes!
Hello! Kobato Hanato speaking!
Kobato?
Oh! I made a mistake! Yomogi Kindergarten!
Who are you?
I'm just someone helping here.
You're certainly full of energy.
Uh, thank you very much!
Where's Sayaka? I'd like to speak to her.
Uh, well um... we're all on our
way out for a picnic.
Do you have business with her?
That's right. I have business with her.
Will you give her a message?
Sure!
Tell her to shut down the silly
kindergarten and move out.
I'm not extending the repayment deadline.
Are you a debt collector?
You people came to the kindergarten
the other day to bully everybody!
Those guys did such a thing?
Huh? Oh, I-I'm sorry!
Why are you apologizing?
Um, it seems I got mad at you
for something you didn't do.
You're a funny kid!
What's going on?
I hate to tell you this, but your
days of helping are over.
I'm shutting down the kindergarten.
No way...
You be sure and tell that to Sayaka.
U-Um, who are you?
Shutting down the kindergarten...
Do you think Ms. Sayaka knows this person?
I'm passing on the picnic.
Ioryogi-san?
I'm going home for a nap.
You took forever!
Man... How long must you keep us waiting?
Thanks to you, we're off to a late start.
U-Um. Is the debt collector an
acquaintance of Ms. Sayaka's?
What?
There was a call a moment ago. From a man.
Said he's shutting down the kindergarten.
It's him.
Don't tell Ms. Sayaka about the call.
But, but, he sounded pretty scary.
Anyway, just keep quiet about it.
Kobato! Fujimoto! We're leaving!
Sorry. We'll be right there.
The entrances are always
in the strangest places.
Bear's Baumkuchen Shop
Hello there!
Hi.
Oh it's you.
I expected more originality in
the name of your shop!
Well, what did you expect?
He told me what to name the shop when
he handed me my occupation.
The guy decides everything, does he?!
Don't call him "the guy."
You get turned into a toy, and still
you haven't learnt your lesson!
I have no lesson to learn!
I haven't done anything wrong!
I can't believe you're still talking like that after
all the ruckus you caused! You idiot!
They hear you talking like that and you're
not getting away with being a toy doll!
They'll reduce you to the size of a thumb doll!
Well, we'll leave that aside for now.
What the heck brings you here today?
Hm? Right...
What is it? Spit it out.
I need you to look into something for me.
Anyway, have a seat. I can at least
hear what you have to say.
Woah!
Look how high we are!
Hey! Look over there!
What is it?
It's a large lake!
I'm shutting down the kindergarten.
I wonder who that was on
the phone this morning.
Kobato!
Toshihiko!
Marina! It's time for lunch!
Okay!
I have a bump here now.
Kobato, you've been through a lot of pain today.
Your attention seems to be elsewhere.
Is there something bothering you, Kobato?
Oh, well...
She's always an airhead.
Not always!
Don't you get Ms. Sayaka worrying
more than she needs to.
Right.
So you're looking for information regarding
the state of Yomogi Kindergarten
and persons associated with it?
Yeah.
What wrong? Did that pathetic new look
strip you of the investigation skills
you used to brag about?
Your looks are tens of thousands of times
more pathetic looking than mine.
I never expected you to talk
to me in that way though.
Huh?
Back then you'd just say "check it".
And if I didn't do as you said, you'd
breathe fire or throw your fist at me.
In that case, I'll give you your wish!
Extra special!
Cut that out already!
Oh, it's done.
This job's too perfect for you!
You're fitting right in I see!
If your men back then saw you
now, they'd be in tears.
The last thing I need is a stuffed
toy telling me that.
Watch your words!
I'll look into it for you.
It's got something to do with that girl, right?
Thanks, man.
Well, especially since you "asked" this time.
This is pretty good.
Woah! Who said you could have any?!
Kobato.
Marina.
What can I do for you?
Kobato, is there something worrying you?
Uh, no... well... um... No there isn't!
Nothing! I'm positive!
So there is something.
It's okay. I'll tell you something good.
If you find it you can be happy.
Kobato! Marina!
Let's play hide-and-seek!
All right!
I'll be right there!
Rock, paper, scissors! One,
two, three! One, two...
Three!
Kobato, you're it!
While you're counting to ten, Kobato, we're all
going to hide. Then come and find us.
Okay! Kobato is ready!
Is this all I get? Darn.
I'm telling you, I could pile dozens of these!
Damn it! This body of mine can be such a pain!
Pretty pathetic too.
I really didn't need to hear that from you.
It's been awhile, Ginsei.
You really do look pathetic.
You shut your face!
So I see you've changed on the outside but
you're still the same on the inside.
Aren't you ever returning to "Ikai"?
I've got things to do.
It's that little girl.
You set one finger on Kobato and
I'll have you for lunch.
Don't you forget, we still haven't
had our deciding match.
What a pain...
Where could everyone have hidden?
They're not anywhere.
Where are you, everybody?!
Oh? Kobato sure seems to be having fun.
Kobato still hasn't even found one of us yet.
Oh, she's looking in some strange place again.
Looks like they'll be awhile.
Everyone, you are very good at hiding.
Hey!
Fujimoto.
We should get going!
Not yet! I'm it right now!
Huh?
The person who's it must find
the ones that are hiding!
Yeah, but it's time to go.
Come on out! We're going home!
Okay!
Oh!
There they are!
K-Kobato are you okay?
Toshihiko and Yoshio! I found you!
Huh?
She's right!
She found us!
Yuzuru and Yukari! I found you!
Oh, Masao! I found you!
And there are more of you over there!
Oh, there too!
Over there too!
Kobato, you've still got a leaf on your head!
You're so silly. Let me get it for you.
Thank you very much.
Shall we go then?
Okay!
Let's take a group picture before we go.
Oh?
Where's Marina?
I don't see her.
Let me go look for her.
Fujimoto.
Ms. Sayaka, please stay
here with the others.
I-I'll go and look for her, too.
Marina!
Did you find her?
No. I wonder if she's still hiding somewhere.
Let's wish.
If I could only have found her sooner.
Let's search over there.
Marina!
Marina?!
She's asleep.
What a relief.
Marina.
Hello there.
Kobato...
Sorry I couldn't find any.
You mean with hide-and-seek?
No, a four-leaf clover.
If you find it, you can be happy.
I wanted to find one for you.
For me?!
Mhm. You didn't seem too happy today, so...
I looked everywhere, but I couldn't find one.
I'm sorry.
It's okay even if you didn't find one.
I'm fine. Because you went and searched for
my happiness. So now I'm happy!
I'm glad!
There's a nice view. Let's take a picture here.
Okay now, don't anybody move!
Fujimoto! Hurry!
I'm okay. You just face the front.
What now?
I found one.
A four-leaf clover.
Here you are.
Thank you, Kobato!
Kobato, look, look!
Look here!
They're all over!
We found lots and lots of happiness.
Hey!
We're taking another picture!
Okay!
Oh no!
Your cake is all crumbled. Cake that
Sir Genko specially gave you.
What is it with you all, one after another?
You're the little helper at the big bear's place.
Uh... I know your name... uh...
Nope. I forgot.
Oh, come on!
The name is Zuisho!
I have a message for you from Sir Genko!
Your requested investigation is complete!
What?!
Hey! Good on him!
Your form doesn't quite suit your cool smile.
Don't be cheeky with me, birdie!
I'm home! Huh?
Ioryogi-san is not home yet.
Oh no! He's so small, perhaps he
got stuck somewhere!
Or maybe he fell off the side of a road!
Or maybe someone squished him!
Oh no, this is a problem!
Ioryogi-san is in big trouble!
Who's in big trouble?
Ioryogi-san!
Hey.
Welcome home.
What's that?
Oh, this?
It's a Baumkuchen.
So how was the picnic?
I have something for you, Ioryogi-san!
Here!
It's a four leaf clover of happiness.
It's a little shriveled, but I found
some happiness for you, too!
I want everybody to stay happy, forever.
Especially everyone at Yomogi Kindergarten.
I report! Regarding Yomogi Kindergarten!
The former principal was apparently
tricked into borrowing money!
Former principal?
Yes. Sayaka Okiura's father.
He died two years ago.
Looks like a real bad bunch who tricked him.
Not only that, one of them seems to
be a relative of Sayaka Okiura.
Sounds like a bit of a mess.
So basically, if left alone, sooner or later Yomogi
Kindergarten will be forced to shut down.
Hito wa mina tonde mitai no ni
Juuryoku ni damasareterunda
Dare mo honto wa toberunda yo
Ano ko ga anna ni kanashisou na no wa
Jibun no kage wo
Dokoka ni wasurete kichatta kara kamo
Sore nara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ni ietara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ga waraeba
Ittari kitari ureshiku naru
Kimi ga shiawase ni naru
Shinpai nante iranai yo
Issho ni iru kara
Ureshikuttemo namida ga deru nante
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Gentle Person.
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Gentle Person.